I've gotten you involved in a weird fight.
我让你们卷进了一场奇怪的纠纷
I'm very sorry for that.
真的很抱歉
-I apologize. -Stop that.
-郑重向你们道歉 -请别这样
You were deceived as well.
理事长你也一样被欺骗了
I'm responsible for what happened.
我得对发生的这一切负责任
Don't worry about me. Just try to get everyone to pass.
别担心我 请尽量让全员通过考试
Give it your all, please.
请全力以赴 拜托了
I said this before, but
虽然已经说过了
I will do so, without question.
但我会这么做的 不用担心
Even so, I'm worried about that boy Yoneyama.
不过 我有点担心那个叫米山的学生
He's your former student who tried to commit suicide, isn't he?
他是你以前那个想自杀的学生吧？
But it really is okay, isn't it?
但那真的没问题 对吧？
If we're going to crush my mentor, it has to be a complete victory.
如果想打败我的导师 非得是压倒性胜利不可
Me too. I want to destroy them completely.
我也一样 我绝对要彻底击垮他
That's a rough turn of phrase.
你这措辞真是粗暴
-You can't stop me. -Listen here…
-你可阻止不了我 -我说你啊…
What bothers me is what Mr. Sakuragi said before we left.
让我在意的是 我们离开前樱木老师说的话
Kumiko. See you later.
久美子 再见了
I heard most residents were opposed.
我听说大多居民都反对
Do you expect to get consent from a majority?
你指望能得到半数以上的同意吗？
Mr. Matsubara.
松原先生
We already have. That's why we're here.
我们已经获得同意了 所以才站在这里
Mr. Matsubara. Is that true?
松原先生 那是真的吗？
Well?
怎么样？
That's what I said at the meeting. Kajitani…
我在会议上是这么说的 梶谷…
Residents in favor
赞成的居民
are close to 50% now.
现在已经接近一半了
But we're struggling to get the final 100 votes.
但我们还在努力争取最后的100票
One hundred votes…
100票…
With integrated resorts,
要建综合度假村
people hear about casinos and gambling and it's an automatic rejection.
人们一听到赌场和赌博 第一反应就是反对
Sheesh!
真是！
I see.
我明白了
I'll come up with a way to deal with that.
我会想办法解决
-Huh? -Can you leave it to me?
-什么？ -你能交给我吗？
Understood.
明白了
We mustn't delay.
我们一定不能再拖了
We've got to use our ace in the hole.
我们得拿出王牌
What's that?
王牌是什么？
Hard cash.
钱
Cash is best for times like this. It can't be traced.
这种时候最好用现金 现金无法被追踪
Giving cash to the opposing residents?
给反对的居民派钱？
If it gets out, you'll lose your license.
要是传出去 你会失去律师执照
Oh, I won't do it. I'll just give the orders.
我才不会去做 我只负责给指示
And I won't leave any trace that I gave the orders.
而且我不会留下任何给指示的痕迹
Whoa, you're scary!
哇 真可怕
You don't want Ms. Kishimoto as an enemy.
我绝对不要和岸本律师为敌
Good thing we're on the same side.
好在我们站的是同一阵线
We're lucky to have connected with you, Mr. Takahara.
高原主任 我们很幸运能和你合作
If the school sale goes well, by next year
要是学校顺利出售
you'll be a prefectural assembly member.
明年你就会当上县议员了
Is that right?
是这样吗？
Yeah, well…
这个嘛…
But Ms. Kishimoto, you're incredible.
但岸本律师 你真是了不起
If we succeed with this plan,
如果这个计划成功
you'll be the legal adviser for the resort.
你就会成为度假村的法律顾问
-I see! -Hey, this vote-getting.
-原来！ -我说 这次拉票
You guys help too.
你们也要出力
A young IT industry genius like you
像你这样的信息技术天才
could easily get their personal information, no?
轻易就能获得 反对居民的个人资料 对吧？
If they have debt.
他们有没有债务
Their income, their families, their weaknesses!
收入、家庭 这一类的弱点
Come on, I'm the president of this company.
我可是这公司的社长耶
Let's use that to our advantage!
好好利用这一点吧！
You'll be rewarded handsomely.
我们会给你一笔丰厚报酬的
That sounds nice.
听起来很棒呢
Now we just need five or more students to get into UTokyo.
现在只需要把五位以上的学生 送进东大就行了
Iwai and Kohashi are out of the running.
岩井和小桥已经出局了
Seto here has 620 points.
濑户得了620分
He won't get in on his Common Test score.
他共通考试的分数不足以被录取
At this point, these three are out.
目前为止 已经有三位出局
There are six left. Fujii, Kosugi, and Kenta Hara will be no problem.
还剩下六位 藤井、小杉、原健太没问题
Amano got 801 on the Common Test.
天野在共通考试获得了801分
At this rate, he should pass.
照这样下去 他应该能通过
This is an important final month for our students.
对学生们来说 这是重要的最后一个月
We don't want them to have any regrets.
我们不想让他们留下任何遗憾
Ms. Mizuno, how much debt does your office have?
水野老师 你们事务所有多少债务？
Huh? Um…
什么？那个…
-About ten million yen. -Yeah? Alright.
-一千万日圆左右 -是吗？好的
I'll take care of that ten million.
我会解决那一千万
But I can't allow you to…
但我不能让你…
You two
你们两位
don't need to worry about a thing.
什么都不需要担心
I want you to focus on the students.
我要你们把所有注意力放在学生身上
I learned something in these ten months.
这十个月我学到了一些事情
Thanks to you two,
多亏你们两位
the students have changed remarkably.
这些学生有了很大的变化
How many years has it been since I saw students with such bright eyes?
我不知道已经多少年没看到 学生有如此明亮的眼睛了
Chairman…
理事长…
Please.
拜托了
Work a miracle for those children.
给这些孩子们创造一个奇迹吧
A miracle…
奇迹…
might just happen.
也许会发生
-Welcome! -Welcome.
-欢迎！ -欢迎
The usual.
老样子
Yes, sir.
是
Yum. Thanks.
真好吃 谢谢
Hey, why don't you say anything?
喂 你怎么什么都不说？
I just came for some ramen.
我只是来吃拉面的
Most would say something.
一般都会说些什么吧
-What? -You know…
-什么？ -那个…
You thought I came to stop you?
你以为我是来劝你的？
-No. -Oh, good.
-才没有！ -那就好
I've got no business with quitters.
我和放弃的人没什么瓜葛
Hey, hey, stop!
喂 等一下！
Who said I quit?
谁说我放弃了？
I told you. I'll take the exam again next year with Kohashi and Iwai.
我跟你说过了 我明年会和岩井还有小桥一起再考
Isn't that called quitting?
那不叫放弃吗？
"Next year"? You haven't even seen the results.
“明年”？你在想什么啊？
You need at least 80% on the Common Test to get into Humanities 3, don't you?
要考上文科三类 至少要在共通考试 拿到80%的分数 不是吗？
I got 620 points.
我只有620分
-I'm not even close. -True.
-还差得远呢 -的确
You might not get into Humanities 3.
你可能考不进文科三类
But you should try for Humanities 2.
但你可以试试看文科二类
Humanities 2?!
文科二类？
Looking at this year's applications,
看今年的申请人数
the cutoff for Humanities 2 will probably be lower than Humanities 3.
文科二类的及格分数 可能比文科三类还要低
You might be able to get in with your 620.
以你的620分 你可能还能考上
If you apply for Humanities 3 and fail the first round, you're out.
要是你申请文科三类 第一关不合格 你就出局了
You'll be done.
一切就结束了
You'll need a high secondary exam score to get into Humanities 2,
要考进文科二类 你得在二试得考到更高的分数
but you can think about that after the first round.
但这是第一关之后才考虑的事情
It's all or nothing. At least apply.
孤注一掷 至少申请吧
All or nothing…
孤注一掷…
What? What's wrong?
什么？有什么问题吗？
Even if you fail, you were going to take it again next year!
即便失败 你本来就打算明年再考的
It's the same either way.
那还不是一样嘛
I suppose that's true.
话是这么说
I've as good as failed.
我已经算是失败了吧
Listen, Seto.
听好了 濑户
Hm?
嗯？
This moment will decide your future.
现在这个瞬间将会创造未来
Will you waste each day
你是会浪费每一天
or do your best to the last second?
或是尽全力 直到最后一秒？
Which do you choose? It's up to you.
你要选择哪个？你说了算
See ya.
再见了
AKIRA SETO CHANGES FROM HUMANITIES 3 TO 2
（濑户辉 决定从文科三类变更至文科二类）
AND ONE MORE PERSON
（另外 还有一人）
Sir.
老师
Yeah? What's up?
啊？怎么了？
After all,
我果然
I want to apply for Sciences 1.
还是想申请理科一类
You said it. "It's not for someone else."
你说过：“这不是为了别人
"Go to UTokyo for yourself."
为了自己上东大”
Those words stuck with me.
这些话一直在我脑海里
I always wanted to go into engineering and build robots, so I chose UTokyo.
我一直都想进入工程领域 制造机器人 所以才选择东大
You told me to switch to Science 2,
你让我转到理科二类
and to Humanities, but…
还有文科 但是…
If I'm going to UTokyo for myself, I want to try for Science 1.
如果我是为了自己上东大 我想试试看理科一类
I'm just helping you find the quickest path.
我只是帮你找最快捷的路而已
But there isn't one way to live life.
但人生的路不只有一条
You can choose the difficult path.
你是可以选择困难的那一条的
It's your life.
这是你的人生
DAYS UNTIL THE UTOKYO SECONDARY EXAM
（东大第二轮考试 还有36天）
COMMON TEST FOR UNIVERSITY ADMISSIONS RESULTS DAY
（大学入学共通考试 成绩发表日）
Huh?
啊？
Aw, c'mon!
什么啊
-Akira! -Huh?
-辉！ -咦？
Why do you put us through so much, Akira?!
你干嘛让我们受那么多罪？辉！
-Guys… -Keeping us in suspense.
-大家… -害我们紧张死了
What do you mean?
什么意思？
You passed the Common Test.
你通过共通考试了
Huh? But I only got 620 points.
什么？但我只有620分
Exactly, it was 620 points!
对啊 正是620分！
The Common Test cutoff line!
共通考试的及格分数！
Look! Humanities 2 is 620!
看！文科二类是620！
Huh?
什么？
Humanities 3 was 700 points, just like he said.
文科三类是700分 就像老师说的
You did it!
你做到了！
Yay! Yay!
太好了！
Everyone gathered in front of the shop and checked the announcement.
大家都聚在店的门口前查看成绩
We were all worried about you and we couldn't look alone.
我们太担心你了 没法自己一个人看
-Even Fujii came. -Huh?
-连藤井都来了 -什么？
I just came to eat ramen.
我只是来吃拉面
Aw, there you go again, Fujii baby.
你又来了 小藤井
DAYS UNTIL THE UTOKYO SECONDARY EXAM
（东大第二轮考试 还有十天）
It's tomorrow, so I'm sure everyone's nervous.
明天就是了 我想大家一定很紧张
They're probably pushing too hard, getting too tense.
他们可能太努力 太紧绷了
Don't worry. I have just the thing.
放心 我早就准备好了
What?!
什么？
Hey everyone, come in.
喂 大家 进来
-Whoa! -What?
-啊！ -咦？
-Isn't that… -No way. Wow.
-那不是… -不是吧？天啊
The actress Mari Kobayashi!
是演员小林麻纪！
Hi.
大家好
Ogata works at a multinational consulting firm.
绪方在一家外资咨询公司工作
Okuno is an engineer at Tokiwa Motors.
奥野在常磐公司担任工程师
I'm sure you all know Kobayashi.
我想大家都知道小林
Why are celebrities here?
怎么会有明星过来？
They're all my classmates from Ryuzan High School.
他们都是我在龙山高中的同学
Thanks to Mr. Sakuragi, they all got into UTokyo.
多亏樱木老师 他们都考上了东大
They've all experienced the UTokyo exam.
他们都经历过东大入学试
They're here to give you advice.
所以来这里给你们意见
This is a valuable opportunity. Ask lots of questions!
这是个宝贵的机会 尽管问问题吧
-Whoa, seriously? -Yay!
-哇 认真的？ -太好啦！
Alright? The UTokyo exam is no picnic.
听好了 东大入学试可不是开玩笑的
People with over 800 on the Common Test have been known to fail.
共通考试成绩超过800分的人 也有不及格的情况
Please don't tell me that now.
现在别跟我说这个啊
Alright, what sort of student makes it through? Fujii.
那么 怎样的学生能够通过？藤井
A student who can stay calm and demonstrate their abilities?
能够保持冷静 并展现能力的学生？
That's right. But that's not all.
正确 但这不是全部
Okuno!
奥野！
I guess it would be…
我想是…
Luck, right?
运气 对吧？
Luck?
运气？
That's right. Students who have luck on their side will pass.
没错 有运气的学生就会通过
How can anyone control that?
这种事没办法控制吧
You're saying we should pray?
你的意思是我们应该要向神祈祷吗？
What are you saying? Everyone here
你在说什么啊？这里的所有人
is already really lucky.
已经很幸运了
In your last year of high school, you met Mr. Sakuragi and Ms. Mizuno.
在你们高中的最后一年 遇到了樱木老师和水野老师
You're the only students in Japan who have that.
全日本就只有你们有这个运气
Oh yeah. You're right.
是这样啊 没错呢
-We really are lucky. -That's right.
-我们真的很幸运 -说得没错
Especially Seto, Hayase, Iwasaki, Amano, and Kenta.
特别是濑户、早濑 岩崎、天野和健太
You already worked miracles.
你们已经创造出了奇迹
Did you forget what terrible grades you all had last April?
你们忘了去年四月那糟糕的分数吗？
It has only been ten months.
才过了十个月
You've got enough ability to pass the Common Test.
你们已经有通过共通考试的能力了
If that's not a miracle, what is?
如果这不是奇迹 什么才是呢？
That's true.
没错
I mean to say,
我想说的是
you can make miracles happen anytime you want.
你们可以随时创造奇迹
Listen. Tomorrow and the next day.
听好了 明天和后天
Just think about yourself.
只考虑自己
You never know what will happen.
你永远不知道会发生什么
Don't think about other people. Just focus on yourself.
别想其他人 专注于自己身上
-Alright? -Yes, sir!
-明白了吗？ -是
You can do it!
加油！
THE DAY OF THE UTOKYO SECONDARY EXAM
（东大第二轮考试当天）
Please, let me win.
拜托了 让我赢
Alright, I'm off.
那么 我走了
Kaede. Your dad made these for you.
枫 你爸爸给你做了这些
He said to take them to the exam.
他说让你带去考试
Go say thank you.
去说谢谢吧
Dad.
爸爸
Thank you.
谢谢
The Olympics are once in four years. The UTokyo exam is every year.
奥运会是四年一次 东大入学试是一年一次
Yeah.
嗯
Off I go.
我出发了
HUMANITIES 3 EXAM HALL
（文科三类考场）
I've experienced this many times in practice exams.
这种场景 我已经在模拟考经历过很多次
Yeah. I can do it like always.
嗯 就像往常一样做吧
Humanities 2 is full of scholars like I figured.
就和我预料的一样 文科二类的考场充满了考生
Whoa, he seems confident.
哇 他看起来自信满满的
She's fired up.
她要火力全开了
Ah! I can't take it!
啊！我受不了了！
Whoa, is he okay?
他还好吧？
Now I think of it, I've got it easy.
现在想起来 我还真是轻松
I'll do it for real next year. I won't get in this year.
我明年再认真考 反正今年考不进
It's just for the experience.
这只是考个经验
Ah, no, no! My headache medicine isn't working!
糟糕了…我的头痛药不奏效！
I worked so hard to stay healthy.
我那么努力地管理健康
I can't believe I'm sick on exam day.
真不能相信 我考试这天竟然生病！
I'm sure there are examinees here who have seen my YouTube.
这些考生中一定有人看过我的视频
Oh yeah, I'll comment my support to everyone.
对了 我可以在上面给大家打气
-Why the rapping? -This is all simple English!
-干嘛要说唱？ -这都是很简单的英语！
Don't underestimate UTokyo!
别小看东大了！
What is all this?
这是什么？
Just like Dad said, even if I fail, I can try again.
就像爸爸说的 即使失败我也能再试
If I don't give up until I win,
要是我在赢之前都不放弃
this is not nearly as stressful as
和奥运会 全国赛 这种一生只有一次的赛事相比
once-in-a-lifetime events like the Olympics or nationals.
这种压力不算什么
Entrance exams are a game. Mr. Sakuragi said so.
入学试是场游戏 樱木老师这么说过
I can play a game with so many people! This is fun.
我能和那么多人 一起玩游戏 真有意思！
Yeah, fun!
嗯 有趣！
Harada. Looks like we got the worst seats.
原田 看来我们坐到了最差的座位
SCIENCES 1 EXAM HALL
（理科一类考场）
Alright everyone, please begin.
好 大家 请开始
There. A rephrasing question.
来了 果然是重述题
Calm down and look it all over.
冷静 先全部看一遍
Think about what the question asking.
想想问题想问什么
It's just like my teachers taught me. It will be okay.
就像老师教过的 没问题的
Whoa! Hey, hey!
哇！这个！
This was a question in a past exam!
这是往年的题目！
Lucky!
幸运！
Eliminate unnecessary information. Concisely.
排除不必要的信息 精简回答
I've never seen this question before! This is fun!
我没看过这一题 这真是有趣！
Yeah, yeah!
嗯！
Aiolocaria hexaspilota.
六斑异瓢虫
They are distributed from Hokkaido to Kyushu, the most common Japanese ladybug.
它们分布于北海道和九州地区 是日本最常见的瓢虫
In winter, they…
冬天时 它们…
He's up to the same things even on test day.
即使是考试天 他也在做同样的事啊
-Hey. -You're all alone.
-喂 -你只有一只
-We have to find your friends… -Hey, Wobbly.
-我们得给你找些朋友… -喂 摇摇先生
Hey, what are you doing?
喂 你在干嘛？
Aiolocaria hexaspilota.
六斑异瓢虫
Huh? What's that?
啊？那是什么？
Hunting for bugs at the UTokyo exam?
在东大入学试抓虫子？
Are you mocking UTokyo?
你是在取笑东大吗？
I don't know how you got through the Common Test.
我真不知道你是怎么通过共通考试的
Tomorrow and the next day,
明天和后天
just think about yourself.
只考虑自己
You never know what will happen. Don't think about other people.
你不知道会发生什么 别想其他人
Just focus on yourself.
专注于自己身上
You just can't stop wobbling, can you?
你身体不能固定啊？
And what's up with your pencil grip?
还有你的握笔姿势是怎么回事？
Just focus on myself today.
今天只专注于自己身上
Focus on myself.
专注自己
Hey, are you listening?
喂 你在听吗？
Let go of that bug!
快放开那虫子！
Quit making that noise! You worm!
别再发出那种声音了！你这只虫子！
Are you listening to me?
你在听吗？
Hey! Hey! Knock it off!
喂！你们开什么玩笑！
-What are you doing?! -Fujii.
-你们在干嘛？ -藤井
Who are you?
你是谁？
The test was too hard and you've gone funny? Just like this guy.
考试太难 让你头壳坏掉了？ 就像这家伙一样
Right? What about that?
对吧？这样呢？
Hey! Stop it!
喂 停手！
You don't know anything! Don't make fun of my friend!
你什么都不知道 别开我朋友玩笑！
Jerks like you will never get into UTokyo!
像你这样的混蛋 是不可能考进东大的！
You'll fail and Kenta will pass.
你会失败 而健太会通过
Huh? You make no sense. Let's go.
什么？说什么啊 走吧
-Apologize to Kenta! -What the hell?
-和健太道歉！ -什么鬼？
Fujii! Are you okay?
藤井 你还好吧？
Let's go. The test is starting.
走吧 考试要开始了
-Show me your hand! -I'm fine.
-让我看看你的手！ -我没事
You're bleeding!
你流血了！
-Nurse's office! -Kenta!
-医务室！ -健太！
I've spent three years getting ready for this day.
我为了今天准备了三年
We can go to the nurse's office after the exam.
我们可以考试后再去医务室
More importantly, Kenta.
更重要的是 健太
Did they bother you during the exam?
他们是不是也在考试对你做了什么？
Excuse me. My friend
不好意思 坐在我朋友
was sitting beside and in front of
旁边跟后面位子的人
two guys who bullied him during the exam.
好像会在考试时欺负他
If something happens in the next exam, please say something.
如果下一场考试 发生了什么事 请您警告他们
Alright, I will.
嗯 我知道了
More importantly, are you okay?
比起这个 你还好吧？
I'm fine. It's nothing.
没事的 这不算什么
Fujii!
藤井！
Thank you.
谢谢
What are you two doing?!
你们俩在干嘛？
Oh, nothing.
没 没什么
If you do anything more, you'll be asked to leave.
再这么做 我就会请你们离开
Yes, sir.
是
It's okay.
没事了
THE UNIVERSITY OF TOKYO EXAM RESULTS DAY
（东京大学 成绩公布日）
Isn't it time to go?
该走了吧？
Yeah.
嗯
Hey, Yuta.
我说啊 裕太
Those YouTube hate comments…
油管上那些酸民…
Don't worry about them.
别担心那些
It was you and Mom, wasn't it? Replying to them.
那是你和妈妈 对吧？回复他们的人
Don't worry about these comments!
别理这些评论 加油
I support you! I hope you pass! Do your best!
我支持你 希望你能通过 全力以赴吧！
I saw them and I felt like I wasn't alone.
我读了以后 觉得自己不孤单了
Thanks to you two, I did my best to the very end.
多亏你们两位 我到最后都尽力做到了最好
Thanks.
谢谢
Selling Tatsumi Gakuen within the year.
一年内售出龙海学园
Our plans are finally moving forward.
我们的计划终于有了进展
Yes, they'll start once we see five students get into UTokyo.
是啊 一旦有五位学生考进东大 计划就会开始
-Takahara. -Yes, sir.
-高原 -是
-It's alright, isn't it? -Yes, I'm sure they'll do it.
-没问题吧？ -是 我肯定他们能做到
The online announcement will be up soon.
成绩很快就会在线上公布
-Let's all hold hands. -Okay.
-大家 我们手拉手吧 -好
I'm sure everyone got in.
我肯定大家都会考上的
Yeah, everyone got in.
是啊 大家都考上
Yeah, got in.
嗯 考上
Yeah.
嗯
-Yeah. -Okay…
-是啊 -那么…
Let's go.
走吧
Let's meet here when we're done.
结束后在这里见吧
Dear god, let everyone pass.
神啊 请让大家都考上吧
-Well? Did it load? -Not yet.
-怎么样？刷新到了吗？ -还没有
Why won't it load?
这网页怎么刷不出来啊？
We should've gone to see it in person.
我们就应该亲自过去看的
No. That's for the students.
不行 要让学生自己去看
It loaded! Mine loaded!
刷出来了！我的刷出来了！
First is Kosugi.
第一个是小杉
Her number is
她的号码是
A30438.
A30428
It's there…
有了
Kosugi passed!
小杉合格了！
Thank goodness! That's great!
太好了！真的太好了！
First one.
第一位
Who else is in Humanities 3?
还有谁考文科三类？
-It's Hayase. -Her number is A31120.
-早濑 -她的号码是A31120
Seto didn't get in…
濑户没考上…
But I know I did.
但我知道我考上了
I was born lucky after all.
无论如何 我天生就很幸运
Hayase didn't get in.
早濑没考上
It's not here.
查不到
Hayase…
早濑…
Next. How about Kenta?
下一位 健太呢？
Sciences 2. His number is
理科二类 他的号码是
A51412.
A51412
I can't get through. Can't get through.
我过不去 过不去
I can't get through…
过不去…
51412… 51412…
51412…
51412. Where? Where?
51412 哪里？
It's there! Mari!
在那里！麻里！
Yeah! Kenta Hara.
好耶！原健太！
He got in!
考进了！
Thank goodness!
太好了！
Thank you very much!
谢谢！
That's our Kenta!
是我们的健太！
How can you traitors live it up…
你们这些叛徒怎么能…
-It's okay. -But…
-没事的 -但是…
Maybe they were dissatisfied with the way I ran the school.
或许他们不满意我运营学校的方式
But they care a lot about the students.
但他们很在乎这些学生
All the teachers at this school are our comrades.
这间学校的所有老师都是我们的战友
Chairman…
理事长…
Who's next in Sciences 2?
理科二类的下一位是谁？
Amano and Iwasaki.
天野和岩崎
-First, Amano… -50174…
-第一位 天野… -50174…
A50174.
A50174
A…50174.
A…50174
I did it…
做到了…
I did it!
我做到了！
Sorry. Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry.
不好意思 借过一下 抱歉
Amano got in!
天野考上了
Congratulations.
恭喜
Dad, Mom.
爸爸 妈妈
God of Badminton.
羽球之神
Please… let me get in.
拜托…让我考上
It's there… It's there!
有了…在那！
It's there!
考上了！
Iwasaki got in! That's four!
岩崎考上了！这样就有四位！
Iwasaki…
岩崎…
She did well, Iwasaki. Alright!
做得好 岩崎 太好了！
She's Olympic material in badminton.
她是羽毛球的奥运会人选
Four students from that school?
那间学校能有四位学生考上？
-That's impressive. -Sakuragi's no joke.
-真了不起 -樱木可不是闹着玩的
Former Chairman, that's four. We can relax now.
前任理事长 已经四位了 我们能安心了
It's still only four. Don't relax yet.
现在只有四位 还不能放松
Last is our shoo-in, Fujii. He'll get in.
最后一位是我们的必胜选手藤井 他一定会考上的
-The last science student is Fujii. -Yes.
-最后一位理科考生是藤井 -是
Sciences 1. Examinee number
理科一类 考生号码
A41811.
A41811
Fujii's number…
藤井的号码…
It wasn't there.
不在那上面
I see.
这样啊
In just one moment,
就在一瞬间
the plan we've worked on for over a year just went up in smoke.
我们努力了超过一年的计划 就这样毁于一旦
Someone will pay.
有人得付出代价
Fujii.
藤井
Mari! Mari, Mari.
麻里！麻里…
I got in! I got into UTokyo!
我考进了！我考进了东大！
-You too? -Yeah!
-麻里也是吗？ -嗯！
-That's great, Kenta! -Yeah, yeah.
-真厉害啊 健太！ -嗯
Congratulations.
恭喜
The same school again.
又是同一所学校了
Yeah.
嗯
Hey, Wobbly.
喂 摇摇先生
Hey, Worm.
喂 虫子
What's this? You got in?
怎么回事？你考上了？
-Come here. -Hey, stop that.
-给我过来 -喂 不要
Shut up!
闭嘴！
Kenta…
健太…
Go on! Hey!
走啊！喂！
You were such a nuisance and you passed?
你这个累赘竟然通过了？
-Screw you! -Stop that!
-去你的！ -快停手！
Out of the way!
走开！
Hey!
喂！
Kohashi? Iwai?
小桥？岩井？
So you're the ones who doted on our sweet Kenta.
宠爱我们家健太的人 原来就是你们啊
I heard you looked after him during the exam!
我听说你们考试时特别照顾他呢
-What do you think you're doing? -I, uh…
-你想干嘛？ -我…
And? Did you guys get in?
然后呢？你们考上了吗？
Hey, how'd you do?
喂 你考得怎么样？
Oh yeah? You failed?
是吗？你落榜了？
I figured!
我想也是！
You two will never get into UTokyo! Get lost!
你们俩是不可能考进东大的！滚吧！
Never come back!
别给我回来！
Kohashi, Iwai. Wow…
小桥 岩井 真厉害…
Four students getting into UTokyo from our school is a miracle!
我们学校有四位学生 能考进东大 真是个奇迹！
And now the chairman doesn't have to step down.
如今理事长不用辞职了
The school won't be sold!
学校也不会出售！
Hip hip hooray, right?
万…万岁 对吧？
Okuda.
奥田
It's not over.
还没结束
There's still one more.
还有一个人
Oh. Akira didn't get in either.
这样啊 辉也没考上
Yeah, he looked like he failed.
嗯 他看起来像是落榜了
He must have also gone home in shock.
他一定是失了魂地回家了吧
Oh, Seto!
啊 濑户！
Hey, Akira! What are you doing?
嘿 辉！你在干嘛？
For next year. I looked around UTokyo.
为了明年 我参观了一下东大
-So you… -Yeah.
-那么你… -嗯
I failed so badly, it wasn't even close. I couldn't even find the first number.
我考得太差 离合格太远了 连第一个数字都找不到
Oh! Weren't you looking at the Humanities 3 board?
哦！你是在文科三类那里吧？
Yeah.
嗯
Seto, you tested for Humanities 2!
濑户 你考的是文科二类
-Oh. -Don't say "Oh."
-啊 -别给我“啊”
Humanities 2 starts with "A2."
文科二类的考生号从“A2”开始
Of course it's not in Humanities 3! Let's go!
在文科三类当然找不到了！走吧！
-Whoa! -Let's go! Let's go!
-啊！ -走吧！
Isn't it over there?
是在那里吗？
Why look? It's not there.
干嘛要看？又不在上面
You never know. What's your number?
很难说的 你是几号？
-A20503! -Sorry, excuse me.
-A20503！ -不好意思 借过
Pardon me.
不好意思
It's there…
有了…
It's there!
有了！
Look carefully. Your number's there!
看清楚了 你的号码在那上面！
No mistake. You got in.
没错 你考上了
Seto got in!
濑户考上了
You got in!
你考上了！
Seto, you got in! Yay!
濑户 你考上了！好耶！
-Congratulations. -Hooray!
-恭喜 -太好了！
I got in…
我考上了…
Me, at UTokyo…
我 在东大…
I'm a UTokyo student!
我是东大生了！
Seto…
濑户…
He passed!
他通过了！
Thank you very much!
谢谢你！
Seto passed.
濑户通过了
There we go!
这就对了！
-Hooray! Hooray! -Man.
-万岁！ -真是
I never thought Seto would get in and I'd fail.
我真没想过濑户会考上 而我会落榜
What a plot twist!
真是个反转
Just kidding.
开玩笑的啦
I should have known.
这也没办法
I never worked hard in my life.
我人生中从来没有那么努力过
No matter how hard I worked,
无论我多努力
it didn't mean much anyway.
结果都不会变
That's not true.
才没有这种事
Nao, you worked really hard.
菜绪 你真的很努力
-Maybe… -You worked hard!
-真的吗？ -你很努力！
You really worked hard.
你真的很努力
Yeah…
嗯…
I'm glad I worked hard with you.
我很庆幸能和你一起努力
Fujii!
藤井！
You're late.
你迟到了
Sorry.
对不起
Sit down.
坐下吧
Amano, Iwasaki.
天野 岩崎
Kosugi, Kenta.
小杉 健太
Seto.
濑户
Congratulations.
恭喜你们合格
You grabbed that passing ticket with your own hands.
你们靠着自己的双手抓住了入门票
How you use it is up to you.
要怎么用它 就看你们了
You can go to UTokyo and pursue your goals
你们可以上东大 追求自己的目标
or use the confidence you got from passing to find a new dream.
或是用你们通过考试得来的自信 寻找新的梦想
I've taught you all I can.
我能教的都已经教给你们了
You can do what you want.
接下来就看你们了
Yes, sir.
是
And the two of you who failed.
还有没有通过的两位
Fujii, Hayase.
藤井 早濑
-You two… -Don't say any more.
-你们俩… -别说了
I did have confidence.
我的确很有信心
I felt like I did way better than the practice exams.
我觉得比起模拟考 这次发挥得要好很多
I'm
我
really,
真的
really frustrated.
真的很沮丧
I've never been so frustrated about anything in my whole life.
我人生中从来没试过 为任何事那么沮丧
I never knew I had this emotion in me.
我从来不知道自己还能有这种情绪
I had no idea.
我一点都不知道
If I never tried for UTokyo,
要是我从来没为东大努力过
I probably never would have known.
我可能永远都不会知道
I'm really glad I tried for UTokyo.
我真的很高兴自己为东大努力过
Mr. Sakuragi.
樱木老师
Ms. Mizuno.
水野老师
Thank you very much.
真的谢谢你们
Fujii.
藤井
Something to say?
你想说什么吗？
After I saw the announcement, I went straight home.
看了成绩后 我直接回家了
Then
然后
I kneeled and begged my parents.
我跪下来求我的父母
Kneeled?
跪下？
I begged them to let me take the UTokyo exam again next year.
我求他们允许我明年再考东大入学试
I'll repeat my third year.
我会复读一年
I asked them to let me study with the UTokyo Special Course.
我请他们允许我在东大专科学习
I'll admit it.
我承认
I'm an idiot.
我是个笨蛋
I was always mocked by my parents and my brothers.
我总是被父母和哥哥们取笑
I wanted to prove them wrong and worked really hard,
我想证明他们是错的 我真的很努力
but now
但现在
I don't care what my family says.
我不在乎我家人说什么了
Fujii.
藤井
You idiot!
你这个笨蛋！
During your important secondary exam,
在重要的第二轮考试中
you hurt your wrist
你伤了手腕
to help Kenta.
就为了帮助健太
I heard from Kenta.
我听健太说了
I knew something happened to Kenta, but
我知道健太发生了一些事 但是
Fujii, you rescued him?
藤井 是你救了他？
When Fujii protected me,
藤井保护我的时候
he hurt his right hand.
他伤到了右手
-Is it my fault? -No.
-是我的错吗？ -不
That day, when I helped you…
那天 帮你的时候…
I was…
我…
so happy.
好快乐
The way I was before, I never would have helped.
以前的我 绝对不会帮忙
But I was able to go help him.
但能够帮助他
I…
我…
I was able to become that person.
能够成为那样的人
I was so, so happy.
我非常快乐
After that, during the test, I got worked up.
后来考试时 心情还是很激动
But I have no regrets.
但我没有遗憾
Kenta, don't worry about it.
健太 别在意
I told you to just think about yourself.
我叫你只管自己的事
You huge idiot!
你这个大笨蛋！
Even so,
不过
with how you are now, you'll get in next time.
现在的你 下次一定能考上
It's a sure thing.
这是肯定的事
You said it. A sure thing.
你说的啊 肯定的事
I said it.
我说的
I'll bet on it if you want.
你要的话我可以打赌
Bring it on!
放马过来！
Okay Fujii, it'll be us four.
好了藤井 那就是我们四人了
We're Team UTokyo Special Course next year.
我们就是明年的东大专科生了
Yeah, let's do it together!
对啊 一起加油吧！
You guys will need two more years, I figure!
你们可能还需要两年吧
Don't say that.
别这么说
Yeah. We're sure to get in next year.
对啊 我们明年一定能考上
Right, Hayase?
对吧 早濑？
Well…
这个…
About that,
这个嘛
I'm good.
我就不了
Huh?
什么？
What are you saying? Are you giving up again?
你在说什么？你又要放弃吗？
No. It's just…
不 只是…
I never told anyone about this, but…
我从来没跟任何人说 但是…
I actually…
我其实…
I got into the School of Business at Aoyama Gakuin.
我其实考上了青山学院大学经营学部
-Huh? -What?
-啊？ -什么？
-He he. -Don't say "he he."
-嘻嘻 -别只是“嘻嘻”啊
Hey, I never heard about that either!
喂 我也没听说过这个！
Sorry, I forgot to mention it.
抱歉 我忘了提起
What? You took the exam?
什么？你去考试了？
For Aoyama Gakuin?
青山学院大学？
I mean, I used my Common Test results. I just put in my application.
我用的是共通考试的成绩 我只是提交了申请
So I didn't have to go to the exam.
不必去考入学试
And I got in, so…
然后我就被录取了 所以…
What? Tell us sooner…
什么啊？早点说嘛…
You're clever!
你太精明了吧
With my personality,
以我这种性格
could I repeat a year to study and try again?
能复读一年再试一次吗？
I'm not confident I could.
我没信心自己能做到
I never really felt like it had to be UTokyo anyway.
反正我从来不觉得非东大不可
I wanted to be a person who could work hard.
我只是想成为一个能够努力的人
So when Kaede
所以当枫说
said "Nao, you worked hard,"
“菜绪 你很努力”
I felt like it was all worth it.
我就觉得全都值得了
Using the Common Test to apply for a private university.
以共通考试的成绩申请私立大学
-I'm sorry. -Why do you need to apologize?
-对不起 -你为什么要道歉？
You researched it yourself and took action.
你自己做了调查并采取了行动
You didn't let another choose your life.
你没让其他人决定你的人生
You thought carefully and chose your path.
你考虑得很小心 并选择了属于自己的道路
Be proud.
你应该感到自豪
Yes, sir.
是
So, next year it will be us three left at this school.
那么 明年这学校就只剩我们三位了
Yeah.
对啊
We're counting on you, sir!
我们就靠你了 老师！
But, this school… Next year…
不过这间学校…明年…
Mizuno.
水野
-But… -What? What?
-但是… -什么？
What's happening next year?
明年会发生什么事？
Hey, I heard from a customer.
那个 我从一位客人那里听说
This place might be turned into a resort.
这地方可能会变成一个度假村
Hey, what are you saying?
喂 你说什么？
You mean the school will be gone? What'll happen to us?
-你的意思是 这间学校会消失？ -那我们怎么办？
Ms. Mizuno. Mr. Sakuragi.
水野老师 樱木老师
They're here.
他们来了
Kumiko, you promised.
久美子 你答应过的
Right here and now, resign as chairman.
你就在这里立刻辞掉理事长一职吧
Can't you hear me? Kumiko, resign.
你听不见我说话吗 久美子？ 快点辞职吧
Yes, sir. A promise is a promise.
我明白了 承诺就是承诺
Poor thing… Because of the students you love, you have to quit.
可怜啊…为了你爱的学生得辞职
The students did well.
学生们做得很好
I am proud of their hard work.
我为他们的努力感到骄傲
Is that right? Now, please sign the paperwork.
是吗？现在 请在这份文件上签名
Yes, now it's official.
是 正式生效了
Kumiko Tatsuno is no longer chairman of this school.
龙野久美子不再是这间学校的理事长
The former chairman has recommended me for the position.
前任理事长推荐我担任这一职务
Can I get a show of approval from the board?
我能请各位理事表决吗？
Please raise your hands.
请举手
Yes, three for, one against.
嗯 三位赞成 一位反对
In following, I, Takahara, am now the chairman.
那么就由我本人高原担任理事长了
Thank you everyone.
请大家多指教
You snake!
你这只狐狸！
I'd like to put forward an emergency motion.
我想提出一项紧急动议
Those in favor of selling the school, raise your hand.
支持出售学校的人请举手
So it's decided.
所以定下来了
Now we have officially decided to sell Tatsumi Gakuen.
我们正式决定出售龙海学园
Takahara.
高原教导主任
Could you call me "Chairman?"
你能叫我“理事长”吗？
You're the worst.
你真是个大烂人
You said you couldn't forgive selling it for money, and now look at you.
你说过绝对不能接受为了钱卖掉学校 你现在看看你自己
You're talking like I'm the bad guy, but it's a misunderstanding.
你说得我好像是坏人一样 但这是一场误会
Listen. Through this decision,
听着 通过这项决定
all the local residents will profit.
所有本地居民都能受益
They should call us their saviors.
他们应该叫我们救世主才对
Right?
对吧？
Saviors? That's a good one. A masterpiece.
救世主？真是个好名字 神来之笔
Yeah.
嗯
Hm? Okay, that's enough.
嗯？好了 差不多了
That's enough.
可以了
Sorry, it was just so funny.
不好意思 这真的太搞笑了
I mean,
这个嘛
you buy the votes of the opposing residents with cash
你用钱收买反对居民的选票
and now you say this!
还说得出这种话！
What do you mean?
那是什么意思？
What… that's unfounded…
什么？那毫无根据…
That's rich, coming from you!
从你嘴里说出来 真是有趣
What are you two saying?!
你们俩在说什么？
Enough fooling around!
别再开玩笑了！
Shut up.
闭嘴
-Yoneyama. -Yes, sir.
-米山 -是
We mustn't delay.
我们一定不能再拖了
We've got to use our ace in the hole.
我们得拿出王牌
-What's that? -Hard cash.
-王牌是什么？ -钱
Cash is best for times like this. It can't be traced.
这种时候最好用现金 现金无法被追踪
-I see. -Yeah, but.
-原来如此 -不过…
Giving cash to the opposing residents?
给反对的居民派钱？
If it gets out, you'll lose your license.
要是传出去 你会失去律师执照
Oh, I won't do it. I'll just give the orders.
我才不会去做 我只负责给指示
And I won't leave any trace that I gave the orders.
而且我不会留下任何给指示的痕迹
Whoa, you're scary!
哇 真可怕
Ms. Kishimoto, what is this?
岸本律师 这是怎么回事？
It's a misunderstanding!
这是误会！
We would never buy off the residents.
我们绝对不会贿赂居民的
Yes. How could we?
对啊 我们怎么可能？
Wow, with this much evidence, can you really say that?
在那么多证据面前 你还能这么说吗？
Huh?
什么？
This is for you.
这是给你的
What is this?
这是什么？
I hope you will vote in favor of building the resort.
希望投票的时候 你会赞成建度假村
Thank you in advance.
先谢谢你了
What should I do? I could send it to the news right now.
我该做什么好呢？ 我现在就能把这发给媒体了
What will the world think of this?
社会大众会怎么想呢？
What are you saying? You're just as guilty.
你说什么啊？你也一样有罪
You used personal information without permission.
你未经同意使用居民的个人资料
-You gave it to us! -Oh, that?
-是你提供给我们这些个人资料的！ -哦 那个吗？
The information I gave you was fake.
那些信息全都是假的
I'd never do such a dangerous thing!
我才不会做那么危险的事
No…
不是吧…
Too bad!
真是可惜
You, a legal adviser for the resort?
你想当度假村的法律顾问？
Say goodbye to your lawyer's license.
和你的律师执照道别吧！
And Takahara, your seat as a prefectural assembly member?
还有高原 你那县议员的位置？
Up in smoke.
烟消云散了
Takahara!
高原！
Give me a break, you jerk!
真是不像话 你这个混蛋！
You couldn't be a politician or an educator.
像你这种人 不管是政治家还是教育者
You're completely unacceptable! You rat!
你都没那个资格 你这个鼠辈！
Hang on, you guys were taking these videos, which means
等一下 你们拍了这些视频 这意味着
you were on our side from the start?
你们从一开始就站在我们这边？
Since when?
从什么时候开始？
Did you know all of this?
难道你全都知道？
You all ganged up to frame me?
你们合伙陷害我？
Sir, did you know?
老师 你知道这些吗？
Huh? How would I know?
什么？我怎么可能知道？
But I did get a feeling.
但我有种预感
They're my former students after all.
无论如何 他们都是我教过的学生
The e-mail about buying the land around the school
那封有关 收购学校周边土地的匿名电邮
sent by an anonymous account. You're the only one who would do that.
就只有你能做到
Impressive as usual, Mr. Sakuragi. You saw it all.
像往常一样厉害啊 樱木老师 你都看透了
We wanted to do it as a surprise for you.
本来还想在最后一刻吓吓你
What are you saying?
什么意思？
We've been working on this for two years.
我们花了两年
Trying to find the one who trapped you.
为了找出是谁陷害你
Right before my exam, two years ago.
两年前 就在我考试之前
I got several e-mails from Mr. Sakuragi.
我收到了几封来自樱木老师的电邮
"You're no good. You won't pass." Over and over.
“你办不到的 你不会合格的” 一封又一封
Huh? I never send e-mails to students.
什么？我从来不给学生寄电邮
Yeah.
对啊
It wasn't you sending those e-mails.
寄那些电邮的不是你
It was Ms. Kishimoto. Wasn't it?
是岸本律师 对吧？
I thought it was odd, so I asked Mr. Sakamoto to look into it.
我觉得很奇怪 所以请坂本先生去查
And I learned that it was sent by you.
然后就发现这些电邮是你寄出的
At the time, I didn't know that.
当时我并不知道
I believed Mr. Sakuragi sent them and I was freaking out.
我坚信那是樱木老师的电邮 我很慌张
Sir!
老师！
Thus, he failed and tried to commit suicide.
所以他考砸了 还试着自杀
Not only that.
不仅如此
In the commotion,
在混乱中
the news reported things that weren't true.
新闻媒体还报道了不实消息
Mr. Sakuragi disappeared.
樱木老师消失了
It was really odd.
这整件事真的很奇怪
The news wasn't accurate, but it was very specific about internal matters.
新闻不准确 但内部事务 却报导得非常具体
It could only be an insider leaking information.
唯一的可能就是内部人员泄露信息
Someone who was against Mr. Sakuragi.
也就是和樱木老师作对的人
And not long after that, Sakuragi Law Office
那之后没过多久 樱木律师事务所
was completely taken over by you.
就完全被你接管了
Don't say such scandalous things.
请不要说这种煽风点火的话
I just made my best judgment as manager of the office.
作为事务所的经营者 我只是做了最理想的判断而已
He didn't do the education consulting work the nation wanted him for
他不想接受 来自全国各地的教育顾问工作
and didn't generate the profit he could.
也没有创造他所能创造的利润
-That sort of person is unnecessary! -Huh?
-这种人是多余的！ -什么？
For the office? For the profits? What platitudes are you spouting?
为了事务所？为了利润？ 你在说什么陈词滥调？
You think I'll accept excuses like that?
你以为我会接受这样的借口？
I feel bad for you.
我对你感到抱歉
I didn't expect you to try to commit suicide.
我没想到你会试图自杀
-But I… -Shut up!
-但我… -闭嘴！
Do you know what I went through because of you?
你知道因为你 我经历了什么吗？
Not just me. You turned Mr. Sakuragi's life upside down.
不止是我 你也扭曲樱木老师的人生
I said it already, didn't I?
我说过了 对吧？
You can't stop me.
你可阻止不了我
Not until I've destroyed you completely.
直到我彻底摧毁你为止
You really did all that.
你真的做出了那种事
You can't complain even if all this proof gets out.
这些证据传出去 你也没法说什么
What do you say, sir?
怎么样 老师？
We can leak everything to the press right now.
我们现在就能向媒体泄露这一切
Leave it at this, Yoneyama.
就到此为止吧 米山
Why? I've worked for two years at this.
为什么？我为了这努力了两年
That's why.
这就是原因
It's for you.
这是为了你
I understand why you want to crush her.
我明白你想毁掉她的原因
But revenge doesn't make anyone happy.
但复仇并不会让任何人快乐
Success gained from trapping someone is empty success.
通过陷害人获得的成功 是空洞的成功
If you've watched Kishimoto for two years, you know.
要是你这两年观察岸本 你就会明白
I don't care what happens to Kishimoto.
我不在乎岸本会怎么样
People like her will fail eventually.
像她这种人最后一定会失败
But I don't want you to go down the same path.
但我不想你和她走上同一条路
Look forward, Yoneyama.
向前看吧 米山
You must live your own life.
你得活出自己的人生
It's like he said.
就像老师说的
If she starts something else, I'll send this out.
如果她再做什么事 我就把这发出去
Nonsense!
太荒谬了！
I've had enough of this farce.
我看够了这场闹剧
It doesn't matter if this gets out. We're still selling.
我不在乎这会不会流传出去 我们还是要出售
At any rate, Kumiko has stepped down.
无论如何 久美子已经退下来了
Stop right there.
等一下
I never knew this was going on.
我不知道背后还有这些事
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
You said you'd leave the methods to us!
是你说让我们处理的
Not only did you buy out the residents,
你不仅收买居民
you tricked the chairman
还瞒骗理事长
and forced the deal without thinking of the students.
强行交易 不去考虑学生福祉
Your methods are too devious.
你的手段太卑鄙了
As the project leader, I cannot proceed further.
作为项目负责人 我无法继续
I'll report this incident to my company.
我会向公司汇报这件事
Good day.
再见了
-Let's go. -Yes, sir.
-走吧 -是
Hey! Wait!
喂 等一下
Stop!
给我停下！
-Father. -Shut up!
-父亲 -闭嘴！
Not the daughter card now!
这种时候别给我打亲情牌！
This happened because you don't do what I say!
事情会变成这样 就是因为你不按我说的做！
Now look at this!
看看现在！
Educational background really doesn't matter.
教育背景真是什么都不是
Everyone around me
我身边的所有人
has amazing educations
都受过良好的教育
and they're all useless, lazy idiots!
但他们都是没用又懒散的笨蛋！
That's not true.
你说的不对
Of everyone here, the most useless and lazy
在座的所有人中 最没用、最懒散的人
is you.
是你
What?
什么？
You make decisions based on short-term business conditions.
你以短期商机来做决策
You tried to sell while the price was high.
试着在价格高涨的时候出售土地
Shut up!
闭嘴！
This school
这间学校
was a terminal case with two years left.
是一个只剩两年寿命的末期病人
My idiot daughter can't turn it around.
我那笨蛋女儿没法扭转局势
-That's why… -You understand nothing.
-所以… -你一无所知
If you thought about the long-term value,
如果你考虑过这间学校的长期价值
you wouldn't have done such a stupid thing.
你就不会做出这种蠢事
Plus, your daughter may have made mistakes.
而且 你女儿可能犯了一些错误
But she was a good chairman.
但她是个很好的理事长
The pillar of the school doesn't need management skills.
学校的支柱不是管理技能
It's strong beliefs as an educator
而是作为教育者的强大理念
keeping the teachers and students in mind.
为教师和学生考虑
Management can be left to someone else.
管理可以由其他人来做
But to support and protect the school,
但要支撑和保护一间学校
the top person must have steadfast beliefs.
另有人一定要有坚定的信念
Chairman Kumiko had that.
这是久美子理事长拥有的
If you can just step out of the way, this school can be rebuilt.
只要你退出经营 这所学校就能重建
Preposterous.
一派胡言
Stop.
等一下
I may have been naive.
我之前也许太天真了
My methods were certainly wrong.
我的管理方式也肯定是错的
But watch.
但你看着吧
I will rebuild this school.
我会重建这间学校
Mr. Sakuragi, Ms. Oink. Long time no see.
樱木老师 小猪 好久不见
Actually I heard from Sakamoto and Yoneyama
其实我从坂本和米山那里听说了
and I've been helping them all along.
我一直在协助他们
FROM YUSUKE YAJIMA
（寄件人：矢岛勇介）
Two years ago, Kishimoto bullied Yoneyama
两年前 岸本为了将樱木老师除掉
in a plan to eliminate Mr. Sakuragi.
不惜霸凌米山
But there was no proof of what Kishimoto did.
但岸本并没有留下证据
So these two infiltrated Kishimoto
于是这两位假装投靠岸本
and waited for her to slip up.
并等她露出真面目
That's why, Oink, don't be mad that they kept it from you.
所以 小猪 别因为他们的隐瞒而生气
You're close to Kishimoto so they kept quiet.
他们不能把这件事 告诉和岸本很亲近的你
There was one more person helping from the shadows.
还有一个在暗中帮忙的人
They'll come to visit you soon.
之后会来见你们
Say hi for me when they come.
到时 请替我和那人问好
-Thank you. -Sir.
-谢谢 -老师
Another message?
又有信息？
You should go to the staff room.
你们最好去一趟教职员室
It's about time for my plan to bear fruit.
我的计划是时候收成了
Ah.
啊
Yes, it was our UTokyo Special Course that produced five successful applicants.
是的 我们的东大专科 有五位学生成功考上了
What? Applying for the new school year?
什么？申请新学年入学？
Thank you. Yes, that's right.
谢谢 是的 没错
Ah, yes. You can find that on our website.
是的 你能在我们网站上查到
What is happening?
到底是怎么回事？
-What's all this? -I planted this.
-怎么突然这样？ -这是我的杰作
Yajima-senpai told me to.
矢岛前辈让我这么做的
FIVE TATSUMI STUDENTS ACCEPTED TO UTOKYO
（东大录取五位龙海学园考生）
Next year they'll have a full class for sure.
明年的班级肯定满员
Didn't you say you'd get a five-year contract?
你不是说你会拿到一个五年合约吗？
You've got work to do.
前辈 你有得忙了
Things will get busy at the UTokyo Special Course.
东大专科的工作会忙起来吧
-Well. Maybe I should help out. -Yeah.
-好 我也该帮帮忙了 -嗯
ONE WEEK LATER
（一周后）
So when is this mystery person coming?
所以那个神秘人什么时候会来？
The other helper that Yajima mentioned.
矢岛那天说的另一个帮手
They'll show up eventually.
最后会来的吧
So it was you who helped out.
果然是你啊 我们的帮手
I just lent them a system that I developed.
我只是把我开发的系统借给他们
Legally, of course.
当然是合法的
Sorry to take up your time, Kosaka.
让你花时间真是不好意思 香坂
It's for the youths with a future.
这都是为了未来有望的年轻人
Also…
还有…
I wanted to repay you a little.
我也想回报老师 一点点也好
-Yoshino! -Naomi!
-良乃！ -直美！
-Long time no see! -How are you?
-好久不见！ -你过得好吗？
I'm good!
很好！
That's amazing. Five people?
真了不起 有五位？
-Yes, five! -That's great! You worked hard.
-是啊 五位！ -太厉害了！你很努力呢
-It was hard! -I'm glad you're well.
-还真不容易呢 -你过得好 真是太好了
Thank you.
谢谢
GRADUATION DAY
（毕业典礼）
Good morning.
早上好
Huh? The tent is gone.
咦？帐篷不见了
-Oh yeah. Sir, did you move? -I guess.
-真的呢 老师 你搬走了吗？ -我想是吧
You can pay your rent now.
你现在能交房租了
Good for you.
真好啊
Just like you guys, I'm graduating.
和你们一样 我也要毕业了
-You're joking. -What are you saying?
-你在开玩笑吧 -说什么啊？
Huh? Really?
咦？真的？
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
Mr. Sakuragi, are you quitting this school?
樱木老师 你要离开这间学校吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Ms. Mizuno, is that true?
水野老师 这是真的吗？
Give me a break. I can't accept that.
别开玩笑了 我没法接受
You promised!
你答应过的！
Yeah. You're leaving us here?
对啊 你要把我们留在这里？
You're getting us into UTokyo, right? We postponed graduation!
你会把我们送上东大吧？ 我们还延毕了！
Kohashi. Iwai.
小桥 岩井
You'll be okay.
你们没问题的
You grew so much in just a few months.
你们在几个月内成长了那么多
You're like dry sponges, sucking up knowledge.
你们就像干海绵一样 不断吸收知识
Your strength is
你们的强项
your sincerity.
就是这股率直
You will definitely get into UTokyo next year.
你们明年一定会考进东大
Believe in Mizuno.
相信水野吧
You too, Fujii.
藤井也一样
You have everything you need to win.
你已具备胜利的所有条件了
Don't give up. Keep going. You'll get it.
别放弃继续努力 你一定会获胜
I, I… I wanted to study with you some more.
我…我还想再向你学习
Kenta.
健太
You'll be a UTokyo student!
你会成为东大生啊！
You'll study at UTokyo.
你会在东大学习
Go and become a good researcher.
去成为一位优秀的研究员吧
I know you'll build a future where people and insects can live together.
我知道你会创建一个 人类和昆虫能够共同生活的未来
Yeah…
嗯…
-Kosugi. -Yes, sir.
-小杉 -是
Never again hold back because of another!
再也不要因为别人而退缩！
You can build any future you want.
你一定能开拓你想要的未来
Yes, sir.
是
Amano.
天野
You're bolder than you realize.
你比你想象的还要勇敢
Don't be afraid of mistakes. Jump in without hesitation.
别害怕出错 毫不犹豫地投入吧
Yes, sir.
是
Iwasaki.
岩崎
With your grit, you can achieve any goal.
凭借你的毅力 你可以实现任何目标
I'm looking forward to the Olympics.
我很期待奥运会
Yes, sir.
是
Hayase.
早濑
You stuck with it to the end.
你坚持到了最后
Combine your natural luck with effort and you're invincible.
把你天生的运气和努力结合起来 你就会所向披靡
-Use it all up. -Yes, sir.
-好好善用！ -是
Seto.
濑户
Yeah.
嗯
You still have a habit of deciding what your limits are.
你还是有给自己设限的习惯
Before you give up,
在放弃之前
ask people for help.
先向人求助
Yes, sir.
是
Listen. All of you. The most important thing in life
大家听好了 人生中最重要的事
is not going to UTokyo, or winning, or getting results.
不是上东大 不是胜利 也不是成绩
It's every moment you spent working towards your goals.
而是你们为目标而努力的每一刻
The effort you spent trying to change your lives.
你们为改变人生所付出的那份努力
That path, that passion.
那道路 那热情
And your love for your friends.
还有对伙伴的爱
That has real value.
那才有真正的价值
Mizuno here changed her life by going to UTokyo.
水野考上东大 改变了她的人生
However.
不过
She didn't just change her own life.
她改变的不只是她的人生
She changed mine too.
她也改变了我的人生
She's meddlesome and gullible.
她爱管闲事 又容易上当
She can't stand by when people need help.
当有人需要帮助时 她没法坐视不理
She's compassionate and cares about her friends.
她很有同理心 非常在乎朋友
She never forgets a favor.
她从不忘记别人对她的帮助
Because of her,
因为她
she helped me get back on my feet when I had nothing.
在我一无所有时 她帮我重新站了起来
Mizuno.
水野
Thank you very much.
谢谢你
Sir…
老师…
Do you remember the words I said?
还记得我说过的话吗？
The only one who can change your shit life is you.
唯一可以改变你们 屎一样人生的人是你们自己
People can't change others.
人无法改变他人
I said that.
我这么说过
But remember this.
但要记得
When you move with pure intentions,
当你怀着率直的心意去行动时
that has the power to move others.
它有着推动其他人的力量
Believe in yourself. Go straight ahead.
相信你自己 勇往直前
If you do, that will bring courage and hope to others.
如果你这么做 你也会给其他人带来勇气和希望
Your passion, effort, and kindness
你们的热情、努力和善良
will move the people around you.
会打动你们身边的人
And that will spread, and change society.
而这会扩散开来 有天会改变这个社会
Build a life, change the status quo!
创造人生 改变现状！
The ones who will build your future
那个建造你们未来的人
are not the nation or your surroundings.
不是这个国家 也不是你们的环境
It's yourselves.
而是你们自己
You idiots are idiots no longer.
你们这些笨蛋不再是笨蛋了
You have friends.
你们有伙伴
Expand that circle.
扩大那圈子
Got it?
明白了吗？
Walk the path you believe in!
踏上你所相信的道路吧！
Nice to meet you!
请多多指教！
We mustn't kill.
我们不应该杀它们
I want to try with all of you!
我想和你们一起奋斗！
I want to join the UTokyo Special Course!
我也想加入东大专科！
I decided to make a move.
我决定直接行动
I want to be involved with badminton.
我想继续和羽毛球有关联
I have good luck.
我有运气
Ugly and stupid can go to UTokyo!
笨蛋和丑女都给我上东大！
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻译：赵慈宇